aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
A Dangerous Sleep
위험한 잠
Space Beast Mognel
Appears
폭수 우주수 모그넬 등장
Heya, I hope you two are healthy!
여어~ 다들 잘 지냈냐?
-Didn't we meet yesterday?
-Good morning, Shin.
-어제 만났잖아?
-안녕하세요, 신
Hey, miss!
저기, 아가씨~
Oh, you're even more beautiful than ever!
오오~ 오늘은 한층 더 예쁜데~
How's this? Would you like to have a tea after school?
어때? 방과후에 차 마시러 가지 않을래?
I guess you ask for that to anyone, Sawamura.
사와무라군은 아무한테나 그런 약속 하지?
Huh? Are you jealous?
얼레? 질투하는거야?
Get real. No way.
그럴 리 없잖아!
-I just can't stand listening to him. From this early morning?
-Really...
-정말 못 듣겠구만, 아침부터
-그러게요
This time, let's enjoy the youth slowly together!
이번엔 단둘이서 느긋하게 청춘을 보내자구
-What an idiot!
-Hey, wait!
-바보같아!
-아악! 잠깐!
Wait for me, miss!
잠깐 기다려~ 아가씨~
That's enough!
작작 좀 해라!
Is it you again?
또 너냐?
His natural enemy appeared.
"천적 등장" 이군요
That's gonna be spectacular!
이거 볼만하겠는걸?
A duty of student is studying, they say.
학생의 본분은 학업에 있다곤 하나
But still, I won't deny all relationships.
모든 남녀교재까지 부정하진 않겠다
It definitely is a good thing.
매우 훌륭해.
But, that only applies when your love is a genuine one.
하지만, 그건 어디까지나 순수한 사랑일 경우의 이야기
Shin, can you make an oath that you love her from your heart?
신, 넌 그녀를 마음에서부터 사랑하고 있다고 맹세할 수 있나?
No, not really...
아니, 그렇게 말해도....
I have a long way to go for my life, and there must be variables in the life too...
아직 이제부터 앞길은 길지 인생은 이런저런게 있지...
You told it.
자, 봐라!
To begin with, your perverse youth clearly shows up in your clothing!
애시당초 너의 그 비뚤어진 청춘은 그 옷차림에서도 나타나 있다!
How unlucky I am, from the morning...
에이, 운도 없구만. 아침부터....
Good job!
잘한다 잘한다!
Good work, Kai! Do it more!
잘한다 카이! 좀 더 혼내주라구
You're not in the position to laugh at someone else!
남 보고 웃을 처지가 아닐텐데, 엔!
This is bad! I'm gonna be involved!
위험해! 나한테도 불똥이 튈 것 같구만!
Wait, En!
기다려, 엔!
No, I must not. Dozing in the class is an embarrassment!
이런, 안돼지! 내가 수업중에 졸다니, 거북할 정도의 수치다!
This room too?
여기도인가?
En! Wake up, En!
엔! 일어나라, 엔!
What's going on?
이건 대체?
Watch out!
위험해!
That was close...
늦지 않았군
Is it this sleeping breath?
이 숨소리 때문인가?
Alright then.
좋아!
Is this guy the cause?
이녀석인가, 사건의 원인은?
Hey, wake up!
에에이! 일어나!
Wheel Kick!
호일 킥!
What kind of guy is this?!
뭐 이런 녀석이 다 있지?!
W- wait for me!
기, 기다려! 이자식!
Huh?
얼레?
Kai!
카이!
Finally you woke up.
이제서야 잠이 깼나?
An incident?
사건이지?
So how's the alien like?
그래서, 이번 우주인은?
It's not an alien. Rather, a monster.
우주인이 아니라 괴수다
Monster?
괴수?!
Interesting! I'm itching!
재밌는걸! 얼른 싸워보고 싶어!
So what kind of guy it was?
그래, 어떤 녀석이었어?
I don't know how to explain well, but...
뭐라 설명을 해야 좋을지..
To be straight, it's slothlike and dirty, but it's frighteningly tough.
솔직히 말해서, 게으름뱅이에 불결한데다가 하지만, 놀라울 정도로 터프한 녀석이야
What's that?
뭐냐, 그게?
That's a weird monster.
묘한 괴수구만
Anyway, the most annoying thing is...
어쨌든, 가장 성가신 건데...
It's that guy again!
또 그녀석이다!
Wh- what was that for, Kai?!
무, 무슨 짓이야 카이?!
It's that guy.
녀석의 짓이다
The breath of the monster makes human fall asleep.
괴수의 숨소리가 인간을 잠들게 해 버려
But we can't also fall asleep because of that.
그렇다고 해서 우리들까지 잠들어 버려선 안돼지
Got it, everyone?
알겠나, 모두들?!
I, I know!
-아, 알고 있어!
-아, 알고 있다구!
Hey, you.
이봐, 당신
Don't you know that you're not allowed around here?
이 주변은 출입금지라는걸 모르나?
We are allowed to kill any suspicious people.
수상한 자는 발견하는 즉시 사살하도록 허가되어 있다
You bastard! Where did you disappear?!
이놈! 어디로 갔지?!
-This way!
-What the?!
-이쪽이다!
-아니?!
You appeared as expected. A Dagwon?
역시 나타났구나, 넌 다그온이지?
You won't stop us this time!
이번엔 방해하지 못한다!
Zargoss Seijin?!
자고스 성인?!
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
It's not a creature of the Earth.
지구의 생물은 아니군요
Maybe a space beast?
우주수(宇宙獸)라고 하면 되려나
Space beast?
우주수?
This breath has an effect of hypnosis.
이 숨소리는 최면 효과를 가지고 있습니다
If we leave it like this, the whole village will fall asleep.
이대로 내버려 둔다면 마을 전체가 계속 잠들게 되어버려
We must find that guy...
녀석을 찾아내지 않으면...
B- but Kai is staying fine for some reason.
하, 하지만 카이는 잘도 말짱하게 있는구나
His nerve systems are different from people like us.
보통 사람과는 신경 구조가 다르다구, 이녀석은..
This is Ryu. I found Zargoss Seijin in the village.
이쪽은 류, 마을에서 자고스 성인을 발견했다
What?!
뭐라고?!
Alright, I'll go join with Ryu! You take care of the space beast!
좋아, 난 류와 합류할게!
너희들은 우주수 쪽을 맡아줘
Alright!
-알았어!
-알겠습니다
Here it is!
여기다!
Is this the one we're looking for?
이녀석인가?
It's still sleeping!
아직도 자고 있어요, 이녀석!
He's messing around with us!
정말 웃기지도 않는 녀석이다!
En?!
엔?!
I'll help you!
내가 도와주마!
Alright!
좋아!
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온!
Shadow Ryu!
섀도우 류!
No running away!
도망친다!
Dammit! It's because of that space beast!
제길! 그 우주수 때문이야!
Alright!
좋아!
How's that?!
어떠냐?!
I will not forgive anymore!
더이상은 안 봐준다!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!
Dag Turbo!
다그 터보!
Turbo Dash!
터보 대시!
Dammit! Now the sound of teeth grinding!
제기랄! 이번엔 코고는 소리랑 이 가는 소리냐?!
It's doing this to weaken us!
우리들을 파워 다운 시키려는 속셈이야!
-What?
-Look at there, En!
-뭐야?!
-저기를 봐라, 엔!
What's that? It's just like an anthill!
뭐야, 저건?! 마치 개밋둑 같잖아!
(역주 : 개미가 흙을 쌓아서 만든 탑)
Zargoss Seijin is trying to make a battlefield.
자고스 성인이 전진(戰陣) 기지를 만들려고 하는거야
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!
Dag Fire!
다그 파이어!
Dammit!
이런 제기랄!
Star Burn!
스타 번!
We must wake this brat up no matter what!
어떻게든 이녀석을 깨우지 않으면..
You can't do it by yourself!
혼자선 무리예요!
Yoku! Let's perform Merging Fusion too!
요쿠! 우리들도 융합합체다!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!
Dag Wing!
다그 윙!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!
Dag Armor!
다그 아머!
Alright! Shoot!
좋아! 쏴라!
We did it!
좋~았어! 해냈다!
It finally woke up!
겨우 잠에서 깬 것 같군요!
Dag Shadow!
다그 섀도우!
It stopped grinding its teeth and snoring!
코고는 소리와 이 가는 소리가 나지 않는걸?
Alright! Time for the demonstration of the true abilities of Dagwon!
좋아! 이제부터가 다그온의 진짜 실력 발휘다!
Blazing Fusion!
화염합체(火炎合體)!
Fire Dagwon!
파이어 다그온!
Here it goes!
에잇! 간다!
Alright, let's go take down Zargoss Seijin!
좋아, 우리들도 자고스 성인을 쓰러뜨리러..
What's it doing?
뭐하는 거래냐?
It must be angry of us for waking up from its happy sleep!
분명, 기분 좋게 잠자는걸 깨워서 화내고 있는 거예요!
What great physical power!
어, 엄청난 괴력이다!
Really, how much will it bother us more?!
정말, 어디까지 속을 썩일 셈이지?!
All three of us with only one hit?!
단 한방으로 우리들 3명을?!
Damn! Are you sleeping again?!
제기랄! 또 자냐?!
Now what should we do?!
뭘 어째야 좋은거야?!
I have a good idea! Start by Chaining Fusion!
제게 좋은 생각이.. 우선, 중련합체입니다!
Liner Dagwon!
라이너 다그온!
Liner Blizzard!
라이너 블리자드!
Finally the snoring is gone!
숨소리가 들리지 않게 됐어
As it became quiet now, it won't bother us for while!
이걸, 아무 소리도 울리지 않으니 완벽합니다!
How's that?! I hope you got your lesson!
어떠냐, 똑똑히 느꼈겠지?!
N- no way!
서, 설마?!
-Impossible!
-You bastard!
-그런!
-이자식!
Dammit! If we fail to destroy that magnetic force generator, the village will be destroyed!
제길! 어서 저 자력 발생 장치를 파괴하지 않으면.. 마을이 파괴되고 말아!
Kai! Fire Dagwon is in a big trouble!
카이! 파이어 다그온이 큰일이예요!
Alright, if then it's all or nothing!
좋아! 이렇게 되면 이판사판이다!
Now, Fire Dagwon!
지금이다, 파이어 다그온!
Alright! Fire Hold!
좋아! 파이어 홀드!
Fire Blade!
파이어 블레이드!
So what should we do with this guy? Make him disappear?
그래서, 어떻게 하지? 이녀석.. 한방에 해치워 버릴까?
We can't leave it like this.
이대로 놔둘 수도 없다구
Thinking about it, it's a poor guy.
생각해 보면 불쌍한 녀석이야
It was used by Zargoss Seijin.
강제로 자고스 성인에게 이용당한 거겠지
I got an idea! Since Kai's the one who found out this guy in first, let's let Kai decide what to do with it.
맞아! 맨 처음 이녀석을 발견한건 카이니까 어떻게 할지는 카이에게 맡기자
Oh, I see! Since it's the job of chief of disciplines to take care of sloths!
오~ 과연! 게으름뱅이를 단속하는건 풍기위원장의 일이니까 말야
I think Kai will do the best for this!
저도 카이가 적임자라고 생각합니다
W- w- wait!
기, 기, 기, 기다려!
I don't want to be associated with such guy anymore!
이런 녀석과 연관되는건 이제 싫다구!
Hey!
이봐!
I think this might be the device that Zargoss Seijin used to carry the space beast.
이건 자고스 성인이 우주수를 운반하는데 쓴 장치가 아닐까?
I'm starved to death!
아~아~ 배고파서 죽을 것 같다~
Me too, I agree. Let's hurry and go back!
나도~ 나도.
얼른 돌아가자구
What's wrong, Kai?
왜 그러세요, 카이?
No, nope. Nothing.
아, 아니. 별거 아냐
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
kaze no naka no PRISM
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
Yoku was examining a weird larva.
요쿠가 조사하던 괴상한 애벌레
It grew up a lot and now it eats, destroys, and rages!
어느새엔가 부쩍부쩍 커져서 먹어대고 부숴대고 날뛰고 있어!
When we realized, the village was full of larvae! Are aliens to blame?
정신을 차려보니 마을은 애벌레로 한가득! 이것도 우주인의 짓인가?!
Yoku! You don't have to examine enemies' disks! You don't know what will happen!
요쿠! 그렇다고 해서 적 원반까지 조사라지 말라구, 무리라니까!
Huh? You got caught?!
얼레? 붙잡혔다구?!
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! Big Panic of Insects
다음회 용자지령 다그온
곤충 대 패닉
Big Panic of Insects
Larvae stealing machine?!
애벌레 훔치는 기계;;?